Guide to the James H. Laue papers, 1936-1999
George Mason University Libraries
- Series 4: Civil Rights Papers, 1956-1988
  - Subseries 4.1: Direct Action and Desegregation, 1956-1988, bulk 1960-1969
    - Emergency Public Integration Committee (EPIC) - Woolworth's Sit-Ins, etc., 1960 (Box 54, Folder 8)
      includes notes, news clippings, press releases, and memoranda
    - Encounter with the Future, May 1965 (Box 54, Folder 9)
      a Southern Regional Council pamphlet by Pat Watters
    - Episcopal Society for Cultural and Racial Unity (ESCRU), part 1 of 2, 1960-1961 (Box 54, Folder 10)
      includes newsletters, reports, memoranda, brochures, articles, and news clippings
    - ESCRU, part 2 of 2, 1962-1964 (Box 54, Folder 11)
    - Excerpt from "I Know Why the Caged Bird Sings", 1969 (Box 55, Folder 1)
      by Maya Angelou
    - Federal Handling of Demonstrations - Hearings before the Subcommittee on Administrative Practice and Procedure, Committee on the Judiciary, U.S. Senate, June 10, 1979 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Fisk University Race Relations Institute, 1960 (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Freedom Ride, part 1 of 2, Summer 1961 (Box 55, Folder 4)
      contains news clippings, articles, reports, memoranda, and press releases
    - Freedom Ride, part 2 of 2, Summer 1961 (Box 55, Folder 5)
      news clippings
    - Genesis of the Southern Negro Student Movement (Sit-In Movement), 1963 (Box 55, Folder 6)
      by Martin Oppenheimer, 283 pages
    - Gil Rowland - South Carolina, 1962 (Box 55, Folder 7)
      includes statistics and statements about race and segregation in South Carolina
    - Highways to Hope - A Tour of the South Following Passage of the Civil Rights Act, ca. 1964 (Box 55, Folder 8)
    - Hot Dissertation Book Notes, 1960-1964 (Box 55, Folder 9)
    - House Un-American Activities Committee: Bulwark of Segregation, 1963 (Box 55, Folder 10)
      by Anne Braden for the National Committee to Abolish the HUAC
    - How the Federal Government Builds Ghettos, February 1967 (Box 55, Folder 11)
      published by the National Committee Against Discrimination in Housing
    - Instructions for Coding Thesis Interviews, 1960 (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Interview - Baker, Ella (19A), March 15-19, 1962 (Box 56, Folder 2)
      transcript, 4.5 hours
    - Interview - Barber, Carroll (1A), February 21, 1962 (Box 56, Folder 3)
      transcript, 3 hours
    - Interview - Bond, Julian, March 2, 1962 (Box 56, Folder 4)
      transcript, 2.25 hours
    - Interview - Bevel, Diane Nash (105), March 28, 1962 (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - Interview - Brooks, Paul (115), March 29-30, 1962 (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - Interview - Campbell, Will (2A), February 21, 1962 (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - Interview - Carr, Lester (46), February 25, 1962 (Box 56, Folder 8)
      transcript, 3.5 hours
    - Interview - Curry, Constance (12A), March 2-11, 1962 (Box 56, Folder 9)
      transcript, 2.5 hours
    - Interview - Dunbar, Leslie (10A), March 9, 1962 (Box 56, Folder 10)
    - Interview - Fleming, Harold (27A), April 5, 1962 (Box 56, Folder 11)
      transcript, 3.75 hours
    - Interview - Forman, James (12S), March 30-31, 1962 (Box 56, Folder 12)
      transcript, 4.25 hours
    - Interview - Gaither, Thomas (24A), March 24, 1962 (Box 56, Folder 13)
    - Interview - Gibson, James (13A), March 12, 1962 (Box 56, Folder 14)
      transcript, 1.75 hours
    - Interview - Galphin, Bruce (22A), March 20, 1962 (Box 56, Folder 15)
    - Interview - Hall, Conant (34), March 4, 1962 (Box 56, Folder 16)
      transcript
    - Interview - Hayden, Thomas Casey (25A), March 21 - April 1, 1962 (Box 56, Folder 17)
      transcript, 4.75 hours
    - Interview - Henderson, Vivian (7A), February 26, 1962 (Box 56, Folder 18)
    - Interview - Hurley, Ruby (17A), March 16, 1962 (Box 56, Folder 19)
    - Interview - Jenkins, Timothy (28A), April 8, 1962 (Box 56, Folder 20)
      transcript, 2.75 hours
    - Interview - Jones, Charles (9S), March 27, 1962 (Box 56, Folder 21)
    - Interview - Jones, Lewis (8A), March 1, 1962 (Box 56, Folder 22)
      transcript, 5.5 hours
    - Interview - LaFayette, Bernard (15), February 24, 1962 (Box 56, Folder 23)
    - Interview - Lawson, James (30AP), March 1, 1962 (Box 56, Folder 24)
      transcript, 1.25 hours
    - Interview - Lee, Bernard (32AP), March 21, 1962 (Box 56, Folder 25)
      transcript, 45 minutes
    - Interview - Levin, Art (14A), March 7-13, 1962 (Box 56, Folder 26)
    - Interview - Miller, Dorothy (15A), March 5-13, 1962 (Box 56, Folder 27)
    - Interview - Long, Herman (5A), February 26, 1962 (Box 56, Folder 28)
      transcript, 2 hours
    - Interview - Long, Margaret (21A), March 2, 1962 (Box 56, Folder 29)
      transcript, 1.5
    - Interview - McDew, Charles, March 5-6, 1962 (Box 56, Folder 30)
    - Interview - McKinnie, Lester (7S), March 24, 1962 (Box 56, Folder 31)
    - Interview - Monsonis, James (55), March 18, 1962 (Box 56, Folder 32)
    - Interview - Morris, John (11A), March 10, 1962 (Box 56, Folder 33)
    - Interview - Moses, Robert (13S), April 7-8, 1962 (Box 56, Folder 34)
      transcript, 3.25 hours
    - Interview - Nashville, February 20 - March 1, 1962 (Box 56, Folder 35)
      transcripts, news release, memorandum, and a survey from Fisk University
    - Interview - Reagan, Cordell (8S), March 27, 1962 (Box 56, Folder 36)
    - Interview - Rollins, Metz (6A), February 25-27, 1962 (Box 56, Folder 37)
    - Interview - Sherrod, Charles (6S), March 22, 1962 (Box 56, Folder 38)
    - Interview - Sitton, Claude (9A), March 6, 1962 (Box 56, Folder 39)
    - Interview - Smith, Kelly Miller (3A), February 24, 1962 (Box 56, Folder 40)
    - Interview - Walker, Wyatt T., March 14-17, 1962 (Box 56, Folder 41)
    - Interview - Whittenstein, Charles (20A), March 15-19, 1962 (Box 56, Folder 42)
    - Interview - Young, Whitney (29AP), April 8, 1962 (Box 56, Folder 43)
    - Interview - Zelner, J. Robert (4S), March 7-16, 1962 (Box 56, Folder 44)
    - Interview - Zinn, Howard (16A), March 14, 1962 (Box 56, Folder 45)
    - Interviews for Sit-In Paper for 284, February - April 1962 (Box 56, Folder 46)
      original interview folders
    - Interviews Schedule for Sit-In Leaders, 1960 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Interviews Schedules, Marginals, Cards, 1960 (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - "Intimidation, Reprisal and Violence in the South's Racial Crisis, 1955-1958,", 1959 (Box 57, Folder 3)
      published jointly by the Southern Regional Council, the American Friends Service Committee, and the Department of Racial and Cultural Relations
    - It Happened in Baton Rouge: A Real Life Drama of Our Deep South Today, April 1962 (Box 57, Folder 4)
      pamphlet by Major Johns and Ronnie Moore, Southern University students expelled for their role in the Civil Rights struggle
    - Journal of Intergroup Relations; Report on the KKK; "In Defense of Black Power", 1960-1965 (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - Journals and Pamphlets on Race Relations, 1960-1969 (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - Kent Lloyd - Articles on Race Relations and Civil Rights, ca. 1964 (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - Kneel-In - General File, 1960 (Box 57, Folder 8)
    - Kneel-Ins in Atlanta, August 7, 1970 (Box 57, Folder 9)
    - "The Labor-Negro Coalition: A New Beginning", May 1968 (Box 57, Folder 10)
      article by Bayard Rustin in the AFL-CIO American Federationist
    - League of Revolutionary Black Workers, ca. 1970 (Box 57, Folder 11)
    - Liberation, Summer and September 1963 (Box 57, Folder 12)
    - "March on Washington: A Study of Effective Organized Protest", September 1965 (Box 57, Folder 13)
      by Albert E. Gollin
    - Marshall Wong - Black/Asian Tensions, 1988-1989 (Box 57, Folder 14)
    - Martin Luther King, Jr. Assassination - JET Magazine and News Clippings, 1968 (Box 57, Folder 15)
    - Martin Luther King, Jr. - "Beyond Vietnam" Speech and Washington Post Article, "The Battle Over King's Papers", 1968, 1988 (Box 57, Folder 16)
    - Martin Luther King, Jr. Center Dedication, January 13-15, 1982 (Box 57, Folder 17)
      newsletters and programs
    - Martin Luther King, Jr. Center for Social Change, 1979-1980 (Box 58, Folder 1)
      newsletters, correspondence, memoranda, and reports
    - Martin Luther King, Jr. - Notes, April 4, 1962 (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - Martin Oppenheimer - "Open Letter to Some Old Friends in the SDS National Office" and "Para-military Activities in Urban Areas", early 1960s (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - Methodist Commission on Social Concerns, 1961 (Box 58, Folder 4)
      notes, newsletters, pamphlets, brochures
    - Miami CORE Institute Sit-Ins, 1959-1960 (Box 58, Folder 5)
      notes, news clippings, memoranda
    - Montgomery News Clippings; MLK Interview and Essay, "Our Struggle: The Story of Montgomery", 1957-1960 (Box 58, Folder 6)
    - "The Movement: Discovering Where It's At and How to Get It", 1970 (Box 58, Folder 7)
      article by James Laue
    - The Movement - What Happened, etc.?, 1965-1966 (Box 58, Folder 8)
      notes, news clippings, and press releases from the Southern Regional Council
    - Muslim Movement, 1960s (Box 58, Folder 9)
      notes and news clippings
    - National Council of Churches Consultation on the Black Manifesto and Black Economic Development Conference, 1969 (Box 58, Folder 10)
    - National Student Association (NSA) in Sit-Ins, 1961-1962 (Box 58, Folder 11)
      news releases, news clippings, mailings, etc.
    - NSA - Southern Student Human Rights Project, part 1 of 2, 1960 (Box 58, Folder 12)
    - NSA - Southern Student Human Rights Project, part 2 of 2, 1960-1961 (Box 58, Folder 13)
    - NSA - United States National Student Association Second Southern Human Rights Seminar, August 9 - September 3, 1959 (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - "The Negro Riots", December 20, 1966 (Box 59, Folder 2)
      by Martin Timins
    - New South: Direct Action in the South, October - November 1963 (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - Newsweek - Black America, June 30, 1969 (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - Newsweek - Black and White, August 22, 1966 (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - Of, By and For the Poor: The New Generation of Student Organizers, June 19, 1965 (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - "The People Take the Lead: A Record of Progress in Civil Rights, 1948-1960" (Box 59, Folder 7)
      published by the American Jewish Committee
    - "A Plan for Black Liberation (Articles by the Progressive Labor Party)", January 1969 (Box 59, Folder 8)
    - "Power, Conflict, and Social Change: The American Racial Case", 1968 (Box 59, Folder 9)
      article by James Laue from Riots and Rebellion: Civil Violence in the Urban Community
    - Provisional Position Statement on the Organization of a National Social Welfare Workers Movement, April 26-27, 1969 (Box 59, Folder 10)
    - Race and Churches, 1959-1960 (Box 59, Folder 11)
      articles, news clippings, newsletters, and press releases
    - Race and Intergroup Bibliography, 1961-1967 (Box 59, Folder 12)
    - "Race Relations Revolution: The Sit-In Movement", 1961 (Box 59, Folder 13)
      by James Laue, 82 pages
    - Racial Mediators Book Proposal, 1975 (Box 59, Folder 14)
    - Rebels with a Cause: A Collection of Essays, edited by Donald A. Hoffman, 1961 (Box 59, Folder 15)
    - "Reflections on a Multi-Racial Society", February 1983 (Box 59, Folder 16)
      by Fanklin Thomas
    - Religion and Race, 1957-1969 (Box 59, Folder 17)
    - Religion and Social Action, 1965 (Box 59, Folder 18)
    - Report of the National Advisory Commission on Civil Disorders, ca. 1968 (Box 60, Folder 1)
    - Report of Observers - Daily Composite, August 24, 1972 (Box 60, Folder 2)
      on violence and disorder at Republican Convention on August 23
    - Reverend Will D. Campbell, 1959-1961 (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - "Revolution in Mississippi", ca. 1962 (Box 60, Folder 4)
      special report by Tom Hayden, president of Students for a Democratic Society (SDS)
    - San Diego (current), November - December 1969 (Box 60, Folder 5)
      articles and memorandum from Carrol Waymon on the future of the Citizens' Interracial Committee
    - The Sit-In Movement in Historical Perspective, November 1961 (Box 60, Folder 6)
      notes and outline for NAIRO talk
    - Sit-In Songs, March 3-4, 1961 (Box 60, Folder 7)
      news clippings and sheet music for NYC recording session
    - Sit-In Successes, 1960-1961 (Box 60, Folder 8)
      notes, news clippings, and CORE direct action statistics
    - "The Sit-Ins: A New Decade and a New Generation?", May 1960 (Box 60, Folder 9)
      essay by James Laue for Social Relations 284 at Harvard, 50 pages
    - Sixties Protest, 1969 (Box 60, Folder 10)
      notes on book with Martin Oppenheimer
    - Sociological Inquiry: Analysis of Race Relations in Current Perspective, Winter 1965 (Box 60, Folder 11)
      journal issue includes Laue article, "Association of Southern Women for the Prevention of Lynching: a commentary on the role of the moderate"
    - South - General - 4 and 9, 1960-1962 (Box 60, Folder 12)
    - Southern Christian Leadership Conference (SCLC), 1960 - September 1961 (Box 60, Folder 13)
      memoranda and press releases from the SCLC
    - SCLC, September 1961 (Box 60, Folder 14)
      memoranda and press releases, notes, and appeal to the president by Martin Luther King, Jr. on the centennial of the signing of the Emancipation Proclamation
    - SCLC, September 1961 (Box 61, Folder 1)
      memoranda, press releases, and correspondence
    - SCLC 6th Annual Convention - Birmingham, Alabama, September 1962 (Box 61, Folder 2)
      sixth annual convention program, press release, and copy of signed letter from Martin Luther King, Jr. to James Laue
    - SCLC 7th Annual Convention - Richmond, Virginia, September 1963 (Box 61, Folder 3)
      pamphlets, notes, and news clippings
    - SCLC 9th Annual Convention - Birmingham, Alabama, August 1965 (Box 61, Folder 4)
      essays, pamphlets, memoranda, etc.
    - SCLC 10th Annual Convention - Jackson, Mississippi, part 1 of 2, August 1966 (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - SCLC 10th Annual Convention - Jackson, Mississippi, part 2 of 2, August 1966 (Box 61, Folder 6)
    - SCLC - Highlander Citizenship School, 1961 (Box 61, Folder 7)
      correspondence, news releases, workshop materials
    - SCLC Newsletters, 1961-1963 (Box 61, Folder 8)
    - SCLC Newsletters, 1964-1966 (Box 61, Folder 9)
      includes some correspondence and memoranda
    - Southern History - Fitzhugh, etc., 1964 (Box 61, Folder 10)
      notes and student papers
    - Southern Law Enforcement - COFO (Box 61, Folder 11)
      includes news articles and Southern Regional Council special report, "Law Enforcement in Mississippi"
    - "The Southern Negro Student Movement: Two Case Studies of Northern Support Movements", 1975 (Box 61, Folder 12)
      article by Laue, 38 pages; includes letter from Martin Oppenheimer informing Laue of publisher rejections
    - Southern Regional Council (SRC) April Sit-In Report, 1960 (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - SRC - Notes, etc., 1959-1961 (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - SRC - Special Reports on Student Protest and Human Relations Activities in the South, September 1959; September 1961 (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - SRC - "The Federal Executive and Civil Rights", January 1961 (Box 62, Folder 4)
      report, 48 pages
    - SRC - Voter Education Project, 1962-1963 (Box 62, Folder 5)
      status report of project and statement of research methods
    - Southern Women for the Prevention of Lynching, 1960 (Box 62, Folder 6)
      correspondence and a graduate essay regarding the Association of Southern Women for the Prevention of Lynching
    - Speeches and Sermons, part 1 of 2, 1960-1966 (Box 62, Folder 7)
    - Speeches and Sermons, part 2 of 2, 1960-1966 (Box 62, Folder 8)
    - Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee (SNCC) - A Special Report on Southern School Desegregation, 1965 (Box 62, Folder 9)
    - SNCC - Atlanta Conference, April 27-29, 1962 (Box 62, Folder 10)
    - SNCC Meeting, August 3-7, 1960 (Box 62, Folder 11)
    - SNCC News Releases, 1961-1963 (Box 62, Folder 12)
    - SNCC Newsletters and Press Releases, 1961-1963 (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - SNCC - Report of the First Meeting, Financial Report, Pamphlets, 1960-1963 (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - Students for a Democratic Society (SDS) Discussion Bulletin, Spring 1964 (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - SDS on the South, part 1 of 2, 1961-1963 (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - SDS on the South, part 2 of 2, 1963-1964 (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - SDS - Stop the Festival of Thieves, Monday, September 15-19, ca. 1968 (Box 63, Folder 6)
      pamphlet for demonstration at International Industrialists Conference
    - "A Study of a Social Movement: The Sit-Ins, ca. 1961 (Box 63, Folder 7)
      by Martin Oppenheimer
    - Survey of the Southern Student Sit-In Movement, 1960 (Box 63, Folder 8)
      U.S. National Student Association
    - "To Establish Justice, To Ensure Domestic Tranquility: Recommendations from the Final Report of the National Commission on the Causes and Prevention of Violence", February 1970 (Box 63, Folder 9)
      thirty page pamphlet
    - "USML Group Proposes Desegregation Plan Process, 1977-1979 (Box 63, Folder 10)
      press releases and memoranda
    - The Urban and Social Change Review, Vol. 3, No. 2, Spring 1970 (Box 63, Folder 11)
      contains Laue's article, "The Movement: Discovering Where It's at and How to Get It"
    - Violence and Dissent in Urban America, 1969 (Box 63, Folder 12)
      includes Laue's article, "Social Change, Dissent and Violence"
    - Voice of the Ghetto, Report on Two Boston Neighborhood Meetings, July 1967 (Box 64, Folder 1)
      by the Massachusetts State Advisory Committee to the U.S. Commission on Civil Rights
    - Voter Registration Drive, 1965 (Box 64, Folder 2)
      foundations, organizations, SRC, Branton, etc.
  - Subseries 4.2: Community Relations Service (CRS), 1965-1971
    This subseries documents Laue's work for the CRS under the U.S. Department of Justice in the mid to late 1960s, where he became the head of Program Evaluation and Development. Materials include reports, meeting minutes, correspondence, personnel files, and speeches.
    - The 7 Cs, 1965 (Box 64, Folder 3)
      notes, articles, and correspondence pertaining to Laue's seven-stage model of racial conflict and change
    - Annual Reports, 1965-1966 (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - Articles on Racial Conflict and Mediation, 1968 (Box 64, Folder 5)
      includes correspondence
    - Book Proposal, October 1974 (Box 64, Folder 6)
    - Brochures, 1974-1975 (Box 64, Folder 7)
    - "Comments on Problem Census and Crisis Goals Discussion from Our Previous Meeting", March 21, 1971 (Box 64, Folder 8)
    - Community Values and Conflict, 1967: A Conference Report (Box 64, Folder 9)
    - Conference on Urban Revolt in Atlanta, October 6-8, 1967 (Box 64, Folder 10)
    - Corrected Calendar, 1969 (Box 64, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1965-1969 (Box 64, Folder 12)
    - Evaluation of CRS Field Services, 1969 (Box 64, Folder 13)
      includes articles and a memorandum on the implications of Nixon's inaugural speech for CRS
    - Evaluation of Summer Activities, June 15 - September 15, 1967 (Box 64, Folder 14)
    - Files, 1965-1967 (Box 65, Folder 1)
      correspondence, memoranda, draft reports, news articles
    - Files, 1968-1969 (Box 65, Folder 2)
    - History (Filed March 1969), 1964-1968 (Box 65, Folder 3)
      correspondence, memoranda, annual reports, notes, news articles
    - Personnel - Atlanta - Bob Hughes, December 4, 1968 (Box 65, Folder 4)
    - Personnel - Baltimore - Jerome Mitchell, 1968-1969 (Box 65, Folder 5)
    - Personnel - Birmingham - James Mills, December 5, 1968 (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - Personnel - Boston - Bragdon, January 15, 1968 (Box 65, Folder 7)
    - Personnel - Chicago - Clark Roberts, November 23, 1968 (Box 65, Folder 8)
    - Personnel - Cincinnati - Nate Allen, November 22, 1968 (Box 65, Folder 9)
    - Personnel - Cleveland - Howard McKinney, November 22, 1968 (Box 65, Folder 10)
    - Personnel - Dallas - Greenwald, November 20, 1968 (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - Personnel - Denver - Clemith Houston and Ramirez, November 18, 1968 (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - Personnel - Detroit - C. Walker, ca. November 1968 (Box 66, Folder 3)
    - Personnel - East Bay, California (Richmond, Berkeley, Oakland) - Bob Brown, November 18, 1968 (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - Personnel - Gary - Sam Dennis, November 22, 1968 (Box 66, Folder 5)
    - Personnel - Houston - Melvin P. Sikes, November 18, 1968 (Box 66, Folder 6)
    - Personnel - Jacksonville Field Report, August 24-26, 1966 (Box 66, Folder 7)
    - Personnel - Los Angeles - Gonzalo Cano and Vivian Strange, November 19, 1968 (Box 66, Folder 8)
    - Personnel - Milwaukee - Mason, November 21, 1968 (Box 66, Folder 9)
    - Personnel - Mississippi Delta - Marjorie Curet, December 5, 1968 (Box 66, Folder 10)
    - Personnel - Mahlon Griffith, December 4, 1968 (Box 66, Folder 11)
    - Personnel - Natchez, Mississippi - Evaluation, November 1965 (Box 66, Folder 12)
    - Personnel - Natchez, Mississippi - Interviews with Conciliators, December 6-13, 1965 (Box 66, Folder 13)
    - Personnel - Natchez, Mississippi - Interviews with Participants, December 7-9, 1965 (Box 66, Folder 14)
    - Personnel - Newark - Copland / Ford, November - December 1968 (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - Personnel - Philadelphia - Hadfield / Walker, November 13, 1968 (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - Personnel - Pittsburgh - Fred Gary, November 14-26, 1968 (Box 67, Folder 3)
    - Personnel - San Antonio - Pompa, November 19, 1968 (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - Personnel - South East Region - Fred Miller, Law Enforcement, December 4, 1968 (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - Personnel - St. Louis - Lewis, November 21, 1968 (Box 67, Folder 6)
    - Personnel - Washington, D.C. - Gault, November 12, 1968 (Box 67, Folder 7)
    - Printed Materials, 1965-1977 (Box 67, Folder 8)
      pamphlets, brochures, and annual reports
    - Program Evaluation and Development (PED) - Ongoing Operation, 1968-1969 (Box 67, Folder 9)
    - PED Retreat, 1968 (Box 67, Folder 10)
    - PED Staff Meeting, 1967-1969 (Box 67, Folder 11)
    - Proposed Civil Rights Act of 1966, May 1966 (Box 67, Folder 12)
    - Speeches, part 1 of 4, 1966-1968 (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - Speeches, part 2 of 4, 1966-1968 (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - Speeches, part 3 of 4, 1966-1968 (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - Speeches, part 4 of 4, 1966-1967 (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - Staff Orientation, June 27 - July 1, 1966 (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - Teacher Training and Community Relations, 1969 (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - U.S. Department of Justice Field Review, January 1969 (Box 68, Folder 7)
- Series 5: Academic Papers, 1947-1990
  This series contains materials from Laue's work as a student, scholar, and teacher. The series is divided into two subseries. Subseries 5.1, Student Papers, covers Laue's academic career from childhood in River Falls, Wisconsin through college and graduate school at Harvard. The subseries contains sociology papers Laue wrote as a student, college notebooks, course materials, church sermons, and correspondence with professors. Subseries 5.2, Professional Papers, covers Laue's academic career as a researcher at the Harvard Medical School Laboratory of Community Psychiatry, as a professor of sociology and urban studies at Washington University-St. Louis and the University of Missouri-St. Louis in the 1970s and 80s, and as a professor of Conflict Resolution at George Mason University in the late 80s and early 90s. The subseries contains journal articles and commencement speeches written by Laue, course materials, academic exercises used in workshops on conflict mediation, and biographical materials prepared for annual reviews and tenure application.
  - Subseries 5.1: Student Papers, 1947-1966